切洋葱的秘诀abc-直立着切两半 留着根部
The trick to onions-- cut them inabchalf length wise, but leave the roots on.
然后再竖着切
Then make your vertical slices.
需要一打 你能做得来吗?
Need a dozen. Think you can handle this?
一打就是12个 对吧?
A dozen is 12, right?
接下来 加点芥菜abc-辛辣 好而强的提味作用
Next, we add mustard greens--abcspicy, and they pack a nice punch.
加上对身体很好
Plus, they're really good for you.
增强脑功能 预防风湿性关节炎
Improve mental function, protectabcagainst rheumatoid arthritis.
甚至对某些癌症还有抑制作用
Even inhibit certain types of cancer.
你是要切洋葱还是给他们泰式按摩
Are you going to chopthose onionsabcor give them a thai massage?
它们想要全套服务是没指望了
Well, I guess a happyabcending is out of the question.
你的职责可不包括讽刺我吧
I don't recall adding making snideabcremarks to your list of duties.
只是采取主动而已
Just taking initiative.
秘密配方: 牛肝菌
Secret ingredient: Porcini mushrooms.
你需要用水泡开它们
You want to reconstituteabcthem in bowl of water.
你还需要请个能集中精神超过30秒的助手
You also want to hirean assistant who canabcstay focused for longer than 30 seconds.
我怎么没听见你在切
Why don't I hear you chopping?
给我点时间
Just give me a second.
- 你在开玩笑吧?abc- 很抱歉
- You're kidding me,ght?abc- So sorry.
你还好吧? 需要坐下来吗?
Are you okay? You want to sit down?
我的嘴唇发紫 黄萎病
My lips are blue. Cyanosis.
背和胸部都感疼痛
Pain in my back and chest.
自发性气胸
Spontaneous pneumothorax.
- 你在说些什么?abc- 我是个医生
- What are you talking about?abc- I'm a doctor.
- 是吗?abc- 我需要医生
- You are?abc- And I need a doctor.
- 你流口水了abc- 闭嘴
- You drool.abc- Shut up.
暂时停用
TE*******
我知道汽油贵了abc但我可以载你一程啊
I know gas is expensive, butabcI could've given you a ride.
电梯坏了
Elevator's broken.
我从接诊处过来时还是好的
It was fine when Iabccame up from admitting.
Dana Miller  癌症研究学者
Dana miller, the cancer researcher.
自发性气胸发作
Spontaneous pneumothorax.
好薄的档案
Awfully thin file.
她刚入院
She just got admitted.
很多原因会引发气胸
Lots of things can cause pneumothorax.
为什么不让10个8个别的医生abc帮我们做无聊的排除法
Why don't we let eight or ten otherabcdoctors rule out the boring stuff?
我们想接这个病例
We wanna take this case.
她可能再用5到10年就能攻克眼癌
She's maybe five or ten yearsabcaway from curing retinoblastoma.
对治愈绝症有既得利益的人有莫大吸引力
Which would make this case attractive to anyone whoabchas some vested interest in people curing the incurab.
她没患慢性阻塞性肺疾病abc不吸烟 没潜过水
She hasn't suffered from copd. She doesn'tabcsmoke. She hasn't been scuba diving.
插管后氧气水平还是很低
O2 sats are low evenabcafter chest tube insertion.
很多病都能导致气胸
Pneumothorax could beabcsecondary to a bunch of things.
囊肿性纤维化 肺癌
Cystic fibrosis, lung cancer.
或者乐观点说 不明过敏原abc引发的晚发性哮喘
Or, to be slightly more optimistic, late-onsetabcasthma triggered by an unknown allergen.
我们有病例了?
We have a case?
你才来上班?
Did you just get to work?
我是不是有麻烦了?
Am I in trouble?
你搭电梯上来的?
Did you take the elevators up?
是啊
Yes.
用治哮喘的类固醇?
So, steroids for asthma?
对 做个CT扫描 查过度充气迹象以确定
Yeah. Do a ct looking forabchyperinflation to confirm.
我还以为我的医院算高科技的了
I thought my hospital was high-tech.
都得等上一天才能做CT扫描
I'd have to wait all day for a ct.
House医生有点特权
Dr. House gets a few perks.
他有自己的扫描仪?
He has his own scanner?
不 只是医院手续对他非常宽松
No, just very loose interpretationsabcof hospital procedure.
我对这些特殊照顾心存感激 但-
I appreciate theabcextra effort, but--
我们对社会大众的一点心意
our gift to society.
想早点让你重回岗位
We want to get you back toabcwork as soon as possible.
我没在工作了
Well, I'm not working.
至少不在当医生了 我辞职了
At least not as a doctor I quit.
8个月前就离开了
I left eight months ago.
你是指短期休息?
You mean, like, a sabbatical?
我患了子宫肌瘤 良性的
I had a uterine myoma. Benign.
但它破裂了 我做了紧急手术
But it ruptured and Iabcneeded emergency surgery.
当躺在手术台时我想abc"现在还不能死 我还没开心过呢"
I was lying there on the table thinking,abc"I can't die now. I haven't been happy yet."
你就不能买辆昂贵德国跑车abc搞点婚外情什么的?
Couldn't you just buy an overpricedabcgerman sports car, or have an affair?
跑车只能满足我一些愿望
My sports car is doingabcwhat I want when I want.
现在我向纽约最牛的厨师学习管理厨房
Right now I'm learning how to run a kitchenabcfrom one of the best chefs in new york.
你去洗锅捣蒜泥?
You're washing pots and smashing garlic?
捣蒜泥让我很开心
Smashing garlic makes me happy.
以前花了8年研究 12年做实验
Before that it was eight yearsabcstudying, 12 years in that lab.
我一直做着我该做的abc而不是自己想做的事
It was always what I was supposedabcto do, and never what i wanted to do.
过来 看看这个 过来
Come here. Look at this. Come here.
可爱
Adorable.
电梯老坏
Elevators keep crashing.
水星逆转了还是怎样?
Is mercury in retrograde or what?
电梯挺反复无常的
Elevators can be capricious.
有时是让你感觉故意跟你为难
Sometimes it just seemsabclike they're out to get you.
她总玩毯子 为什么她要这样呢?
She keeps playing with theabcblanket. Why would she do that?
为什么你会认为电梯要故意为难我?
Why do you think the elevatorsabcwould be out to get me?
不知道啊
I don't know.
也许它想休假陪陪它的小电梯
Maybe they wanted to take time offabcto spend with their little dumb waiter.
但却不得不把它丢给家里的电梯保姆
But they the had to leave itabcat home with an elevator sitter
就因为你令替补电梯不干了
because you drovetheabcreplacement elevator to quitting
因为你谁的话都不听 只听我的
because you're incapable ofabclistening to anybody but me.
只是个想法
That's just a theory.
你错了 我连你的话也不听
You're wrong. I don'tabceven listen to you.
你要么干活要么回家
Either do your job or go home.
别把我扯进来
Leave me out of it.
我在干活
I am gonna do my job.
但不代表我会愉悦地工作
It doesn't meanI have to do it happily.
不代表我能不带怨气工作
Doesn't mean I have toabcdo it wiout resentment.
更不代表我不会找机会abc报复那个害我在这的人
And it definitely doesn't meanI have to do it withoutabcseeking vengeanceon the person making me be here.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你正式把我拉下到你的水准了
You've officially draggedabcme down to your level.
好
Okay.
你好啊 Blue
Hey, blue.
不是哮喘 肺活量正常
it's not asthma. Lung volume is normal.
她确实在8个月前割除了子宫肌瘤
She did have a uterineabcmyoma removed eight months ago.
中心线静脉注射有可能在肺附近穿孔abc孔慢慢扩大了
Central line iv could have made a holeabcnear the lung that slowly expanded.
胸膜无增厚
No pleural thickening.
不敢相信她不干了
I can't believe she quit.
人是有权利去追求快乐的
People have the right to be happy.
肿瘤科轮值的时候我见过abc一个患眼癌的4岁小孩
I saw a four-year-old withabcretinoblastoma on my oncology rotation.
癌细胞侵蚀了她眼 扩散到脑部
The cancer had eaten through herabceye and into her brain.
世上存在着恐怖的疾病
Horrible diseases exist.
不代表人们应该为此放弃娱乐和其他
It doesn't mean people shouldabcgive up recreational anything.
为什么不? 大局来看-我不管abcJonas Salk的人生是不是悲惨
Why not? Big picture-- I don't care ifabcjonas salk's life is a miserable shell.
只要他能治小儿麻痹
I just want him to cure polio.
你的人生不能总是''大局为重''
You can't live your life "big picture."
还得照顾自己和自己关心的人
You've gotta look out for yourselfabcand the people you care about.
那为什么你要做医生?
Well, then,why are you a doctor?
而不是坐在斐济的游泳池边畅饮朗姆酒
Why aren't you sitting by a poolabcin fiji knocking back mai tais?
人类都是利己动物
People act in their own self-interests.
你们在此是因为在此快乐
You're all here because you'reabchappy to be here.
至少因为在此已是最佳选择
Or at least because it'sabcyour best option.
我是因为想帮人才来的
I'm here because I want to help people.
不 你是因为帮人使你快乐
No, you're here because it makesabcyou feel good to help people.
Taub和 Foreman是因为别无选择
Taub and foreman are here becauseabcthey've got no other viable choices.
13急迫地想在死前 使人生有点意义
And thirteen is desperate to makeabcher life matter before it's over.
这么说...你乐于在此?
So... you're happy to be here?
像吗?
Does it show?
这些是...肺间质纹理增多
Are those... increasedabcinterstitial markings?
可能是肺纤维化
Could be pulmonary fibrosis.
做个活检
Do a biopsy.
Foreman
Foreman.
"你得照顾那些自己关心的人"
"You've got to look out forabcthe people you care about."
这不会跟你给13换真药
That wouldn't have anything to do withabcyou screwing over your clinical trial
从而毁掉临床实验有关吧?
by slipping thirteen theabcreal drug, would it?
你说这样做很愚蠢
You said that would be stupid.
她知道吗?
Does she know?
因为Jonas Salk可不会批准
Because jonas salk would not approve.
没什么可告诉她的
There's nothing to know.
好了?
Got it?
-好了?abc-好了
- Good?abc- Yep.
- 你还好吧?abc- 只是有点头痛
- You okay?abc- Just a headache.
- 我服了点镇痛药 但-abc- 哪里疼: 前额还是后脑?
- I took some ibuprofen, but--abc- where's the pain:Front or back?
前额
Front.
为什么这些卡的图画总那么无趣
Why are there never any interestingabcpictures on these cards?
他们该弄个黄版的
They should make a dirty version.
尖锐的疼 还是抽疼-
A sharp pain,orabcmore of a throbbing--
别担心 不是副作用
relax, it's not a side effect.
头痛很正常
People get headaches.
没错 我还是给你做个核磁共振吧
True, but I can get you an mri.
我要是用的是真药abc都已经几星期了
If I'm on the drug,it's been weeks.
不会忽然这时候才出问题的
It's not like something'sabcgoing to suddenly crop up now.
好吧 第一张卡
Okay. First card.
火车 鸭子...
Train, duck...
不记得了?
you can't remember?
钢琴
Piano.
我们需要活检来确认-
We need aabcbiopsy to confirm--
你需要开肺活检abc确认是否肺纤维化
you need an open-lung biopsytoabcconfirm pulmonary fibrosis.
是个入侵性手术
That's invasive surgery.
我得好几个星期不能上班
I'd be out of commission for weeks.
并无冒犯之意 但你没再工作了
No offense,but you're not working.
多躺一会又如何呢?
What does it matter if youabcspend a little time in bed?
没工作不代表我没地方可去呀
Not working doesn't mean Iabcdon't have places to go.
我有读书会 钢琴课 烹饪课
I've got my book group, pianoabclessons, cooking classes.
他们使我开心
They make me happy.
一份温暖的苹果天妇罗也使我开心
A warm apple fritter makes me happy.
但不能实现我的人生价值
It doesn't fulfill meas a person.
在这工作就能实现价值了?
And working here does?
要不是的话 我早就回去给人抽脂了
If it didn't,I'd have found aabcway to go back to tucking tummies.
好样的 你的工作能实现价值abc又让你开心 很罕见
Well, good for you. If your job fulfillsabcyou and makes you happy, that's rare.
我没说我开心
I didn't say I was happy.
我喜欢当整形医生
I loved being a plastic surgeon.
报酬 生活方式
The money, the life style.
现在这份工作有很多缺点
And in a lot of ways this job stinks.
薪水只有几个子儿 整天都很烦-
I'm making five bucks,I'mabcalways annoyed...but--
你可以扪心自问 "我今天过得很有意义"
you can look yourself in the mirror andabcthink, "I did something worthwhile today."
正是如此
Exactly.
这很重要 我也确实怀念这种感觉
Well, that's important.abcAnd I do miss that.
但还是不够
But it jus wa't enough anymore.
感觉不太对
That doesn't feel right.
坐起来
Sit up.
感觉很怪
Oh, that's weird.
怎么了? 腹积水?
What is it? Ascites?
你的腹部里都是血
Your belly's full of blood.
一开始她的肺缩小abc就像我洗完冷水澡一样
first her lung deflates,likeabcme after a cold shor.
现在她的肝出血 像我-
Now her liver startsabcto bleed,like me after--
你没事吧?
you okay?
好得很
great.
只是为小丑大学面试练习一下
Just practicing myabcclown college audition.
有人弄了绊马索
Someone set a trip wire.
我们一直跟病人在一起
We were with the patient the whole time.
我们在药物试验处
We were in the grc.
肺 肝 说吧
Lung, liver, go.
你也不困扰是谁干的吗?
Shouldn't you be obsessing overabcwho did this to you?
不-有人给病人做了磁共振abc查肿瘤吗?
nope--anybody bother mriingabcour patient's liver for tumors?
无肿瘤 无囊肿 无明显病因
Uh, no tumors, noabccysts,no clear etiology.
你要是不困扰 就肯定知道是谁干的
If you're not obsessing, youabcmust have already figured it out.
是的
yes.
我困扰的是为啥你不困扰abc病人的肝为啥忽然裂了缝
So I'm obsessing about why you're not obsessingabcabout why our patit's liver suddenly sprang a leak.
肝尾状叶有个小点 可能是囊肿
There's a tiny spot on theabccaudateobe. Could be a granuloma.
腐蚀了肝动脉 引起出血
Erodes intothe hepaticabcartery, causes the bleed.
是什么引发囊肿呢?
What caused the granuloma?
芽生菌病
Blastomycosis.
可能已经潜伏了几个月
Could have been a symptomatic for months.
侵袭她的肺部abc我们让她服用类固醇
It hits her lungs,we give her steroids.
真菌加快生长并攻击肝脏
It blossoms and attacks her liver.
取一片肺组织 放在紫外灯下
Get a piece of her lung,stickabcit under a black light.
如果发亮的话 喜欢她做的abc甜品的病童就可以松口气了
If it glows, sick children who needabcher souffles can breathe easier.
Foreman
Foreman.
又来了?
Again?
你有麻烦了
You have a problem.
- 我说过了 我没有--abc- 你是真的有麻烦了
- I told you, I didn't-- -abcthen you really have a problem.
她要把头转过去才能看到MRI片
They way she turned herabchead to look at the mri...
她的周边视觉正在衰退
I think she's losingherabcperipheral vision.
只因为她转了一下头?
Because she turned her head?
我真替你高兴
I'm happy for you.
你爱得如此之深abc不惜冒着吊销执照的风险
A love so deep you're ready to chuck yourabcmedical license to give her powerful,
好让她服用一种abc未经试验 有危险副作用的药物
unproven drugs withabcdangerous side effects.
我不知你对我的爱有多深
I don't want to make any assumptionsabcabout your feelings for me,
但我的生日快要到了喔
but I do have a birthday coming up.
我听说Cuddy麾下三军abc已经吹起了进攻号角
I hear cuddy's sealabctraining finally came in handy.
我要不要先找件防弹衣穿上?
Should I be investing in a flak jacket?
你很安全
You're safe.
没有地毯式轰炸?
No carpet bombing?
不火烧德累斯顿 给她点颜色看看?abc(德国城市 二战中被轰炸毁灭)
No burning of dresden toabcteach her a lesson?
鉴于你从不采取正当竞争手段
Well, since you're incapable ofabctaking the high road,
我猜你正策划一起大规模abc长周期的大反攻
I assume there's some deeper,abcmore long-term strategy in effect.
Cuddy不是跟你过家家
Cuddy's not playing games.
不是等着你还击
She's not looking for leverage.
她要的是彻彻底底的复仇
She wants pure,unadulterated vengeance.
而你就这么乖乖由着她了?
And your counter-moveabcisto let her have it?
还击的最佳时机是abc我有所要求的时候
The only time to strikeabcbackis when I want something.
现在我要求的正是abc让一切回复正常
All I want now is to getabcthings back to normal.
所以我不能让冲突升级
Which I can't get by escalating.
赢得这场战争的唯一办法是以退为进
The only way to winabcthis waris to lose it.
让她搬石头砸自己的脚
Let her punch herself out.
这个解释也说得通
Yeah, that makes sense too.
"也"?
"Too"?
我还以为 你是因为使得abc她们母女分离而感到内疚
I was thinking you actually feel guiltyabcabout taking her away from her baby.
但你这个解释也不错
But your explanation's good too.
虽然有违你的本性 但是...
It's completely inconsistent withabcyour character, but...
谢了 唐僧
thank you,rationalization man.
你挽救了咱们全村
You have saved the village.
吃饭么?
You wanna eat?
你把文件落了
You forgot your file.
Dana Miller? 那个癌症研究学者?
Dana miller? The cancer researcher?
现在不是了
Not anymore.
Miller博士 还记得我吗--
Dr. Miller, I doubt ifabcyou'll remember me--
James Wilson 对不?
james wilson, right?
在芝加哥的腺癌研讨大会上
Chicag the adenocarcinoma conference.
好记性
Impressive.
你需要可的松止痒吗?
You want some cortisone for that itch?
肝功能衰竭
Liver failure.
痒是副作用之一
Itching is one of theabclovely side effects.
你为什么要辞职?
Why did you quit?
最糟的是 每次生病看医生abc都会有一大帮人对我评头论足
The worst thing  is now every time I get sick,abcI have to listen to a dozen people judge me.
难不成要我恭喜你?
Do you want me to congratulate you?
我手上有4个癌症儿童abc正在死亡边缘挣扎
I've got four kids in ped-oncabcright now who are gonna die.
其中3个活不过一年abc另一个也许只有几天了
Three of them within a year,abcthe other in a few days,probably.
研究早晚会取得突破
Breakthroughs will happen.
不管有没有我在 总会有人找到答案
With or without me,someoneabcwill find the answer.
也许吧
Maybe.
我- 我...
I--i...
我是负责前线的
I'm in the trenches.
我只能和一个又一个敌人周旋
I'm--I'm doingabctriage as best I can.
而你有机会彻底结束这场战争
You had the chance to end the war.
我这样的人怎么还能坚持战斗abc当你这样的人都已...
How is someone like me supposed to keepabcfighting when someone like you just...
放弃了?
walked away?
当我辞去工作时 很多人都很生气
When I left my job, a lot ofabcpeople were furious with me.
冲我发火 要比承认自己不开心容易
It was easier to be angry thanabcto admit they weren't happy.
他们沉浸在过去的生活中abc为其所累 无法作出新尝试
That they were stuck in a ruts omewhereabcin their lives, unable to move forward.
你的负累是什么?
What's your rut?
够了 盯得我发毛了
Okay, you're freaking me out.
你说我们要不要生孩子?
Do you think we should have kids?
我们讨论过这个问题
We've had this conversation.
那是10年前了 一切都不一样了
Ten years ago. Things change.
我们第三次约会时abc我明说了我不要孩子
On our third date I told you thatabcI didn't want to have kids,
你说你不介意
and you said that youabcwere okay with that.
我当时这么说abc是为了和你上床
I said it because Iabcwanted to sleep with you.
后来我爱上了你
And then I fellin love with you.
才发现自己真的不介意
And I realized that Iabcreally could be okay with it.
不是说我想孩子想得发疯
It wasn't like I had this burningabcdesire to have children.
上帝 你因此怨恨我? 所以你才--
God, have you been resentingabcme all this time?Is that why--
不 当然没有
no. Of course not.
我只是...突然想到了
I'm just... revisiting.
我不是说着玩玩的
This isn't a whim for me.
我经过深思熟虑才abc作出了这个决定
It's not a decision that I made lightly.
你没有想过 有了孩子会怎么样?
Don't you ever wonder whatabcit would be like?
我一直都在想
All the time.
但还不足以让我付诸实践
Just not enough to make me want to do it.
我喜欢我们现在的生活
I like our life.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
我能不能开电视?
Could you turn the tv back on?
向前看
Look straight ahead.
今早为什么不做这个测试?
Why didn't we do this test this morning?
- 能看到吗?abc- 不能
- You see that?abc- No.
糟糕
Damn.
我的周边视觉正在衰退?
I'm losing my peripheral vision?
我在药物组
I am on the drug.
那你是不是得向他们报告abc并让我停止服药?
Does this mean you have toabctell them and take me off it?
是 也不是
No, and yes.
据他们所知 你服用的是安慰剂
As far as they'reabcconcerned,you're on the placebo.
我上星期发现了
I found out last week.
试验证明药物起作用了...
The trial was getting positive results...
所以我换了你的药
so I switched you.
那么说我的头痛...
So my headaches...
只要我停止服药abc就什么事也没了
I'll stop taking the drug,andabceverything should be fine.
样本对芽生菌病测试呈阴性
Specimen's negative for blasmycosis.
就这样了?
That's it?
我通知House实验结果 你去告诉病人
I'll go give house the testabcresults. You can tell the patient.
我们才约会两个星期
We've been dating for two weeks.
你就冒着违反试验规范abc和自毁前程的危险
You just broke trial protocol andabcrisked your entire career
让我服用不知能否帮到我的药物
to give me a drug we're notabceven sure will help me.
我一时无法接受
I don't think I'm ready for that.
Miller医生?
Dr. Miller?
对不起 测试呈阴性
I'm sorry. The test was negative.
所以我要停掉你的--abc你的头怎么了?
So I'm gonna take you off--abcwhat happened to your head?
我不知道 我在睡觉 觉得很痒
I don't know. I wasabcsleeping. It's so itchy.
你在睡梦中挠痒
You were scratching it in your sleep.
把头挠破露出了头骨
You scratched right through your skull.
这是脑浆
This is brain matter.
来人帮忙啊!
Need some help in here!
我给她做了个自由皮瓣缝合abc以免留下疤痕
I did a free flap closure toabcavoid any scarring.
算她走运-- 破损没有导致脑损伤
She was lucky--the scratching didn'tabccause any brain damage.
但她术后醒来说的第一件事abc还是觉得很痒
But the first thing she said when weabcwoke her up was it still itches.
痒的传感器只存在于皮肤表面两层
Itch receptors are only inabcthe top two layers of skin.
就是说 她不是真的痒abc而是她以为自己很痒
Which means she's not actuallyabcitchy, she just thinks she is.
就是说问题出在脑子里?
So the problem's in her brain?
谢天谢地有你给我们解释
Thank god we have youabchere to interpret that for us.
对不起 我很头痛
Sorry, I have a headache.
可能是心理问题的abc她作出了人生的重大决定
could be psychogenic. She madeabcbig, sudden change in her life.
可能是心理失衡导致的
Could be the resultabcof a mental imbalance.
她做自己想做的事abc这有什么问题?
She wants to dowhat she wantsabcto do. What's crazy about that?
那她为什么非辞职不可?
why do you have to quit to do it?
我做某件事 是因为我想去做
If I want to do something,I do it.
如果能找到平衡 就不会钻死胡同
If you can figure out aabcbalance,there's no burnout.
谢谢你的人生宝贵一课
Thanks for the lesson,deep.
痒痒是昨天开始的 不是8个月前
The itching startedabcyesterday,not eight months ago.
脑膜炎 脑炎...
Meningitis, encephalitis...
都是扩散性的疾病 只有局部病发abc可能是斑块
those are diffuse processes. Thisabcis localized. could be plaques.
多发性硬化症可以解释 也许在肺部
Ms would explain,possibly the lungs.
也可能是脑瘤
So would a brain tumor.
能不能别坐着瞎猜abc去做个头部MRI证实?
Well, how 'bout we stop guessingabcand mri her head instead?
要不要谈谈你的头痛?
You want to talk about your headaches?
不太想
Not particularly.
你把药停了 但头痛更严重了
You went off the drug,butabcthe headaches are worse.
你需要做MRI
You need an mri.
需要MRI的是病人
The patient needs an mri.
如果她感染了坏疽abc你会不会把我的腿锯掉?
If shead gangrene,wouldabcyou be amputating my leg?
药丸里含有可待因?abc(鸦片类镇痛药)
Those pills have codeine in them?
你吃的是指定剂量的两倍
You're taking twice the indicated amount.
我离开药物不过24小时
I've only been off the drug for 24 hours,
我想你不满是因为我abc离开了你24小时吧
so I think the bigger issue here isabcthat I've been off you for 24 hours.
你的症状包括头痛加剧abc周边视觉衰退
You have worsening headaches,lossabcof peripheral vision,
还有长期讳疾忌医的劣迹
and a long history of pretending badabcthings aren't happening.
你以为只是因为我不满吗?
You really think this isabcjust about my hurt feelings?
我什么时候把你降职了?
I don't remember demoting you.
我给你带来点东西
I brought you something.
最新一期育儿杂志
The latest issue of parent magazine.
这个专栏很有趣
Really interesting column.
研究表明 在职母亲比全职妈妈abc更投入 更细心
Apparently, working moms are actually moreabcengaged and attentive than stay-at-home moms.
因为个人成就感什么的
Something about personal fulfillment.
这只是职业妇女为不能陪伴孩子找的借口
That's just a rationalization by workingabcmoms to justify not being with their kids.
她们有权选择 但不是我想要的生活
Which is fine,if that's whatabcthey want. It's not what I want.
这是一本护士季刊
And this is nurses quarterly.
重点是--
Theabcpoint is--
你来这里的唯一目的是把abc脏兮兮的拖把水溅到我的地毯上
you're only here to get back at me byabcdumping dirty mop water on my carpet.
要干就快些 让我专心工作
Just get it over with soabcI can get back to work.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我想...我们当中总得有人承担风险
I figured... I don't know, oneabcof us needed to go out on a limb.
我以为能帮你
I thought I could help you.
我要保持不动 很难和你交谈
It's hard to have a conversationabcwhen I'm trying not to move.
噢 上帝
Oh, god.
MRI什么也没查出来
Patient's mri was negative.
没有肿瘤 没有损伤
No tumors,no lesions.
你的拐杖呢?
Where's your cane?
你们的同事呢?
Where are your coworkers?
- 我拷过他们了abc- 仍有可能是心理问题
- I paged them.abc- It could still be psychogenic.
客观来说 哪来"仍有"这个可能abc这个可能从来都不成立
Technically,it c't still be that,abcbecause it never could be that.
她在睡梦中把头都挠穿了
She scratched through herabcskull while she was sleeping.
除非她做了关于虱子的噩梦
Unless she was having aabcdream about fleas--
真巧你正好路过
Funny you should drop by.
正在讨论我们的病人呢
We were just talkingabcabout this patient of ours.
给他说说 两个医生不在时abc发生了什么事-- 你要去哪里?
Tell him the part about where two of herabcdoctors don't show up--where are you going?
多发性神经炎 不是脑子的问题abc而是神经
Polyneuropathy. It's not inabcthe brain,it's in the nerves.
解释了痕痒 还有肺和肝脏的问题
It explains the itching,theabclungs, the liver.
电击受影响的区域abc重启神经 她就会没事了
Shock the affected area,rebootabcthe nerve-- she'll be fine.
Foreman
Foreman.
她的情况有多糟?
How bad is she?
她的视神经交叉有一个肿瘤
She's got a tumor in her optic chiasm.
治疗肿瘤不需要穿上外套
You don't need your coat treat a tumor.
我要去制药公司
I'm going to the drug company.
告诉他们 你毁了他们的试验abc你的医德 还有病人的健康?
To tell them that you compromised theirabctrial, your ethics,and the patient's health?
这真是个好主意
That's a great idea.
他们记录了数百个病人的资料
They have recordsonabchundreds of patients.
我要知道 其他病人有没出现肿瘤abc以及是如何治疗的
I can ask them for access, find out if otherabcpatients developed tumors and how they were treated.
药物抑制细胞的死亡
This drug inhibits cell death.
我能猜到他们是如何治疗的
I think I could take a wildabcguess at how I treat that.
- 停止服药?abc- 没错
- Stop taking it?abc- Yeah.
她昨天已经试过了
She tried that yesterday.
噢 天啊 都一整天了abc她脑子的肿瘤还没融掉?
Oh, my god,it's been a whole day,abcand her brain tumor hasn't melted away?
你走进电梯abc不过是为了求个心里安稳
If you get on that elevator, and it's only'causeabcyou're worried about getting to sleep tonight--
我想告诉她 别的病人也有这种情况abc而且他们好转了
I want to be able to tell her this happenedabcto other people,and they're fine now.
那告诉她得了
So tell her.
我不会骗她的
I'm not gonna lie to her.
现在说这话有点晚了
A little late for that.
你必须等
You need to wait.
因为如果症状不消失abc她需要你有医生执照
Because if this thing doesn't go away, she'sabcgonna need you to still have a medical license.
我和House谈了 他觉得我们应该--
So I spoke with house.Heabcthinks we should just--
- 我的腿流血了abc- 怎么回事?
- my leg is bleeding.abc- What happened?
我去接电话 摔倒磕到了桌子上
I was going for the phone,abcand I fell over the table.
我看不见了
I can't see.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
我什么也看不见了
I can't see anything.
你打算付清洁工小费吗?
You gonna tip housekeeping?
都是Cuddy害的
Get it from cuddy.
不要告诉我-- 她把你的房子给烧了
Don't tell me-- she burnedabcyour apartment to the ground.
她放火倒好 起码暖和
The warmth would have been nice.
没有供暖 没有电
No heat, no power.
有位House太太致电电气公司abc说我们搬家了
Apparently mrs. House called theabcutilities and told them we were moving.
你有17条短讯
You have 17 messages.
看来你的非暴力不抵抗政策不起作用
And your non-involvement strategyabcdoesn't seem to be working.
挂吧 他来了
Hang up, he's here.
我们找了你一晚上
We've been paging you all night.
好哇 接着讨论如何联系不上我abc别管为啥联系我
By all means,let's discuss the failedabcattempts to contact me, not the reason behind them.
我们还没打开机器abc病人就脊髓休克了
Patient started experiencing spinalabcshocks before the machine was turned on.
Lhermitte氏综合征的病症abc(内侧纵束综合征)
Lhermitte's sign.
还没电击就休克了 而且还痒个不停
Shocks without shock,abcan itch that won't stop.
她需要的是苏斯博士abc(美国儿童文学作家)
She needs dr. Seuss.
也可能是白塞氏病 或缺乏维生素B12
Lhermitte's sign couldabcmean behcet's, b-12 deficiency.
没有疼痛 没有贫血 Foreman去哪了?
No sores, no anemia. Where's foreman?
不知道
No idea.
可能是另一种脱髓鞘疾病
Could be another demyelinating disease.
为什么你只问Foreman而不问13?
Why are you asking aboutabcforeman and not thirteen?
因为两个问题指向同一个答案
Because both questions areabcbound to have the same answer.
乌檀木和白象牙总是形影不离abc(Ebony and Ivory 保罗麦卡尼的单曲)
Ebony and ivory are joined near the hip.
别管脑子了 往下看
Forget the brain. Look lower.
脊柱肿瘤解释不了肺和肝脏的症状
The spinal tumor wouldn't explainabcthe liver or the lungs.
但攻击性的脊髓血管瘤可以
But an aggressive spinalabchemangioma could.
找出来
Go find it.
你为什么不应门
You didn't answer the door.
大概是因为我不想和任何人说话
Probably because Iabcdidn't want to talk to anyone.
出去时麻烦把你偷来的钥匙留下
You can leave yourabcstolen key on your way out.
我在找Foreman 我以为...
I was looking for foreman. I figured...
你看不见了
you can't see.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
在去制药公司的路上
On his way to the drug company.
把他叫回来 我替你拨号
Tell him to come back. I'll dial.
说不定他们能帮上忙
If they can help.
你以为制药公司有对付肿瘤的独门魔棒?
You think that drug company has a magicabctumor wand that no one else knows about?
你需要放射治疗abc而不是牺牲Foreman
You need radiation,abcnot ritual sacrifice.
他换掉你的安慰剂前 问过我的意见
He asked for my advice beforeabche switched you off the placebo.
我告诉他 如果他爱你 就去做
I told him to do it if he loved you.
他只想着他爱我
He only thinks he loves me.
没区别
It's the same thing.
是的 他是个傻子
Yes, he's an idiot.
你没有要求他做任何事abc而且你对他的所做所为很生气
You didn't ask him to do anything.abcYou're pissed off that he did.
所以你让他自毁前程abc好偿还他犯下的过错
So let him torch hisabccareer to pay for his sins.
除非你对这个傻子有感觉
Unless you actually feelabcsomething for the idiot.
如果是这样的话 你让他及时回头
In which case, you might wantabcto tell him to turn around.
你伤害他了
you're hurting him.
好哇 他让我吃了多少多苦头
Good, after all theabcstunts he's pulled on me.
你伤害他的身体
You're physically hurting him.
这才是重点
That's the point.
这算什么重点?
What's the point?
你到底想达到什么目的?
What do you think you'reabcgoing to accomplish?
不能任由House把别人把痛苦里整
House shouldn't be allowed toabcmake people miserable
- 而不必付出代价abc- 你一点也不痛苦!
- without paying for it.abc- You're not miserable!
你能体会我的感受?
You're telling me how I feel?
你在这里 是因为你喜欢在这里
You're here because you like this.
你喜欢和他共事
You like working with him.
哇 原来我是来寻开心abc早知就买下弹弹屋了 (儿童充气玩具)
Wow, if only I'd known I was having fun,abcI wouldn't have canceled the bouncy house.
那好 开除他 然后回家照顾宝宝
Fire him, and go beabchome with your new baby.
我欣赏他为医院做的事情
I like what he does for this hospital.
他对医院有用 因为他是这样的人
What he does is who he is.
你也一样
And the same goes for you.
慢一点
Slow down.
除非你想放射她的心脏abc而不是脑子
Unless you want to radiateherabcheart instead of her brain.
当然咯 这样一来你的麻烦就全解决了
Of course, then yourabcproblems would actually all go away.
谢了
Thanks.
自责还不够深刻
I'm not beating myselfabcup enough already over this.
进入左侧颈总动脉
Entering the left common carotid.
你坏了规矩
You broke the rules.
女友眼睛瞎了
Girlfriend went blind.
你要有失去她的心理准备
You gotta be ready for losingabcto be one of the possibilities.
到了颈动脉分支
You're at the carotid bifurcation.
我知道给她换药 一旦被发现abc会给我带来不好的后果
I knew that giving her the rugabcwould be bad for me if I got caught.
我从没想过会对她不好
I never thought it would be bad for her.
别的病人都没有不良反应
Nobody else was having adverse reactions.
你这么做 是因为你爱她
You did it because you love her.
但讽刺的是 你从未真正替她想过
Ironically, you never tookabcher into consideration.
好想瞧瞧你送她什么作为周年纪念礼物
Can't wait to see what you getabcher for your anniversary.
导管接近了视神经交叉区域 到位了
Catheter's adjacent to theabcoptic chiasm. We're in position.
核素 核素
Nukey, nukey.
大伙儿今天是怎么了?
what's going on with everyone today?
House Foreman还有13都扯进去了
It involves house,foreman, and thirteen,
意味着 是件愚蠢 危险或悲惨的事abc或者兼而有之
which means it's either dumb,abcdangerous, or tragic, or a combination.
我真庆幸自己置身其外
I'm embracing my ignorance.
House关于血管瘤的看法是对的
House was right about the hemangioma.
看来是可治愈的
Looks fixable.
这是什么?
What's that?
血管瘤一般单独出现
hemangiomas travel solo.
这家伙还携带家眷了
This thing has brought a friend.
肺和脊柱旁有肿块
Masses in her lungs and spine.
- 还有个在心包膜abc- 到处都是
- One in her pericardium.abc- They're everywhere.
典型间皮瘤
Classic mesothelioma.
它向外转移到脊柱和肌肉
It metastasized outwardabcto the spine and muscles.
噢 真是嘲讽
Ah, the irony of it.
要不是某些癌症研究员偷懒回家abc或许她根本就不会生病
Maybe she wouldn't be sick at all if some otherabclazycancer researcher hadn't gone home early.
Foreman和13在哪?
Where are foreman and thirteen?
你不是该说"两天前扫描的时候abc没见她这儿有"吗?
Shouldn't you be saying, "those weren'tabcthere when we scanned her two days o"?
间皮瘤不会进展这么快
Mesothelioma shouldn't grow this fast.
很好的改述 让Wilson做活检确定
Good rephrasing. Haveabcwilson do a biopsy to confirm.
不
No.
有些事不对劲
Something weird is going on.
同事被牵扯进来--我们应该知道
It involves ourabccolleagues--we should know.
你想我们治疗病人abc那就告诉我们事情经过
You want us to treat theabcpatient, tell us what's going on.
实际上 他只需要我们让Wilson做事abc所以...
Actually, all he needs us to do isabctell wilson to do something. So...
你总是泄露秘密 然后观察别人反应
you always blab to watch people react.
你不说 说明你不想我们有反应abc不是好事
So not blabbing means you don't wantabcus to react, which can't be good.
13的头痛不仅是头痛?
Is thirteen's headache notabcjust a headache?
如果去入院登记处查 会找到她的名字吗?
If I check with admitting,amabcI gonna find her name?
有一点痛
A little pinch.
那天我很抱歉 我...责怪你...
I'm sorry about the other day.abcI... unloaded on you. And...
你没觉得怪错了
you're not sorry.
你感到难过是因为间皮瘤会要我的命
You feel bad becauseabcmesothelioma means I'm dying.
你是个好人 感谢你的关心
Person. I appreciate the sentiment.
我不是因为你快死了而道歉
I'm not apologizing because you're dying.
我道歉是因为你是对的
I'm apologizing because you were right.
我是有心病
I am stuck.
我女朋友死了
My girl friend died.
她是唯一我爱了很久的女人...
She was the only personabcI've loved for a long time, and...
我依旧住在她的公寓abc被她的东西包围
I'm still living in her apartment.abcI'm surrounded by her things.
让她的东西放在原位
I have left it all exactly where it was.
我不知道怎样才能走出来
I don't know how to get unstuck.
什么都不做才是错的
The only wrong thingabcis... to do nothing.
是啊
Yeah.
好
All right.
那不该发生的
That's not supposed to happen.
你有想过去找制药公司 看他们能否帮忙?
Have you thought about going to theabcdrug company, see if they can help?
我想过
I thought about it.
我们再等等 这才半天
We need to give it moreabctime. It's been half a day.
这玩意儿还在长abc难道要整个脑子腾出空来装
This thing keeps growing, there's otherabcstuff in your brain you might need later on.
如果我只是一般病人abc你俩这会儿在休息室吃油炸圈
If I were any other patient, you'dabcboth be in the lounge,eating donuts.
- 你不是别的病人abc- 好吧
- You're not any other patient.abc- Right.
别的病人你不会感到愧疚
Any other patient,you don't feel guilty.
但你不用为了过失而将事业付之一炬
But you don't get to torchabcyour career to pay for your sins.
House让她那样说的 是吗?
House told her to say that,didn'te?
难道不对吗?
Does that make it any less true?
你觉得他是对的?
You think he's right?
谁在乎? 你这个伪君子
Who cas? You're a hypocrite.
你没问过她是否想要吃药
You don't ask her if sheabcwants to be on the drug,
但当有机会让她好起来时
but when there's a chance youabccould help her get better,
突然你又让她自己决定?
suddenly you're lettingabcher call the shots?
这可不高尚 这是在擦屁股
That's not being noble.abcThat's saving your own ass.
他的事业毁了我会更难过
I'd feel worseif heabcdestroyed his career.
间皮瘤不会出血
Mesothelioma doesn't bleed.
是什么导致出血的肿块?
So what causes masses that do bleed?
血吸虫病导致动静脉畸形
Avm's secondary to schistosomiasis.
她体内会有蠕虫乱爬 我们没看到
She'd be crawling withabcworms. We'd have noticed it.
溶骨症和血管瘤伴血小板减少综合征abc都能导致超级侵略性血管肿瘤
Gorham's disease and kasabach-merritt canabcboth cause super-aggressive vascular tumors.
病人心跳停止
Patient's heart just stopped.
这又是什么导致的?
So what causes that?
心包填塞 血液进入心包膜 压迫心脏
Cardiac tamponade. She's bleeding intoabcher pericardium, smothering her heart.
注射器
Syringe.
血压回升 见效了
B.P.'S going back up. It's working.
不 没有--看
No, it'sabcnot--look.
现在输血小板 新鲜冷冻血浆abc所有能让她情况稳定的东西
we're transfusing platelets,ffp,abceverything to try to keep her stable.
但恐怕补不及血液损失
But we can barely keepabcup with the blood loss.
照这个速度 她今晚就会死
At this rate, she could beabcdead by the end of the day.
我们必须切除血管瘤 阻止出血
We need to resect the vascularabctumors, stop the bleeding.
太晚了-- 现在没外科医生敢碰她
Too late--no surgeon's gonnaabctouch her now.
我们该放弃? 让她流血而亡?
Should we give up?abcJust let her bleed out?
别这么傻
Don't be silly.
那得提高职业过失责任险费率多少点啊?
You know what that would do toabcour malpractice insurance rates?
采取主动
We go on the offensive.
切断侵略军补给线
Cut off the invading army's supply line.
你是说栓塞?
You're talking about embolization?
切断供给血液给肿瘤的动脉abc肿瘤就会衰亡
Cut off the arteries that feed bloodabcto the tumors, they wither and die.
从肺部开始
Start with the ones in her lungs.
如果肿瘤长大 她会呼吸困难
If they get any bigger, she'sabcgonna have a hard time breathing.
要告诉我们她要死了 都会很困难
So she'll have a hardabctime telling us she's dead.
杀死肿瘤是 无法避免伤害健康组织
You can't kill the tumors withoutabcalso killing healthy tissue.
如果我们毁了她3/4的肺...
If we wipe out3/4 of her lungs...
祈祷马拉松长跑不在她的爱好名单上
let's hope that running marathonsabcwasn't on her happy list.
我找到了这个
I found this.
在 衣橱里
In the, uh, coat closet.
藏它的地方
Where I hid it.
以为再也见不到你了
Thought I'd never see you again.
小小Greg
Little, little greg.
是啊 你听到我了!
Yeah, you heard me right!
你还是老样子
Well, you are who you are.
让人讨厌 但...这不是你的错
It's annoying, but...abcit's not your fault.
不是你 我...
It isn't about you. I...
对不起
I'm sorry.
因为你在孩子出现之前都干得很好
Because you were doing this jobabcperfectly until the baby came along.
什么?
What?
我在道歉 你就不能接受我的--
I'm apologizing.Can'tabcyou just accept my--
我接受
I accept.
每隔28天 我们就得这样跳一轮舞?
We gonna have to do thisabcdance again in 28 days?
你到底怎么了?
What the hell is wrong with you?
昨天 你恨我
Yesterday, you hate me.
今天 你几乎要趴在我肩上哭
Today, you're practically weepingabcon my shoulder.
我只能猜想 是你大姨妈来了
I can only assume that what I'mabchearing is your aunt flow telling me...
当我像个混蛋时 你突然变好心肠
when I was being aabcjerk,you suddenly act human.
当我想和好了 你又变回混蛋
But when I act human,youabcturn back into a jerk.
我们的周期没同步吧
Guess our cycles aren't matched up yet.
这是你说接受我道歉的方式 对吧?
This is your way of sayingabcyou accept my apology, isn't it?
不 我是说你以前工作得很蹩脚abc以后会更蹩脚
Nope, this is my way of saying you were doing a crappyabcjob before; you will a slightly crappier job now.
地球接着转 生活和育儿的本质都如此
Everything keeps going. Natureabcof life. Nature of parenthood.
你一直在演戏
Or this whole thing is just an act.
现在回到了你认为该扮演的角色
And you've gone back to theabcpart you think you need to play.
你该和Wilson谈谈
You should go talk to wilson.
唐僧需要忠实的伙伴
Rationalization man needsabca faithful side kick.
现在 理智的人去拯救生命
Now, rational man needsabcto go save a life.
House 如果你在找可回收瓶abcKutner已经清理走了
House. If you're looking for returnableabcbottles, kutner's already cleaned it out.
见鬼! 噢 也好
Damn! Oh, well.
意味着 掏出来唯一的东西...
That means the only thingabcI'm gonna get out of this...
就是诊断结果
is a diagnosis.
护士给她卫生巾替代棉条
So the nurses gave herabcpads instead of tampons.
这和诊断有关吗?
Is that diagnostically relevant?
护士为什么要给她用护垫呢
Fact that the nursesabchad to give her anything is.
意味着她子宫内流血
Means she's bleeding from her uterus.
女人都有 很正常 没啥好怕
Women do that. It's perfectlyabcnatural. Not scary at all.
她来月经 她全身都在出血
She menstruating andabcshe's bleeding everywhere.
28天里有3 4天如此 可以叫巧合
There's about a 3 or 4 in 28abcchance it's a coincidence.
更有可能是子宫内膜异位
Which leaves a much bigger chance thatabcthe diagnosis is ectopic endometriosis.
八个月前她有子宫肌瘤
She had a myoma eight months ago.
医生切入子宫壁
Surgeons cut through her uterine wall.
每一刀都有可能将子宫内膜细胞abc带入血液循环
Every cut of the scalpel could have sentabcendometrial cells spilling out into her bloodstream.
有些进驻在肺 有些在肝 或者脊柱
Some of them took up residence in herabclungs, some in her liver,some in her spine.
就像所有蓬勃的内膜细胞abc它们成长繁殖到临界点
And like all horny little cells, they went forth andabcmultiplied till they reached a critical mass.
到了下一个周期 当她子宫膨胀的时候abc所有内膜细胞群都膨胀
In the days leading up to her next period, whenabcher uterusis supposed to swell, everything swelled.
当子宫该出血时 所有着陆点都出血
And when her uterus was supposedabcto bleed, everything bled.
是的 女士 我在责怪她的周期
Yes, ladies,I am blaming her period.
这算得上最糟糕的经期
Granted, it's the worst period ever.
同时来经期实在糟糕
Although, frankly,not by all that much.
切掉肿块 她就没事了
Cut out the masses,she'll be fine.
得等到周期结束 不出血了才能手术
Can't do surgery until her cycle'sabcover and she stops bleeding.
那我们祈祷她能撑到那时
Well, let's hope sheabccan hold out till then.
别干等 给她曲奇 冰淇淋和海摊风光片
In the meantime, get her a pint of cookieabcdough ice cream and a dvd of beaches.
对不起
I'm sorry.
Foreman?
我能看见你
I can see you.
感觉如何?
How you feeling?
和前几天比 棒极了
Relative to the last few days, awesome.
你差点死了
You almost died.
8个月来的第二次
For the second time in eight months.
我明白
I know.
这次有什么新的人生感悟?
How do you feel about yourabclife choices this time?
我没有躺在这儿想过"如果?"
I didn't lie there thinking "what if?"
我总担心 我在临死前会想abc"我没做过什么真正重要的事"
I always worry,on my death bed I'll think,abc"I didn't do anything really important."
你只有一天会面临死亡
You're gonna spend one day ofabcyour life on your death bed.
其余的25,000多天才是我们应该操心的
The other 25,000 are the onesabcwe should be worrying about.
今晚做个好梦
Go to bed happy tonight.
Schmidt医生
Dr. Schmidt.
这是Eric Foreman
It's eric foreman.
坦白说 试验出了问题
actually,he trial isn't going too well.
你告诉他们了 是不是?
You told them,didn't you?
你确实没其他选择...
Well, you really had no choice...
对个傻瓜来说
on account of being an idiot.
他们停止用药?
They gonna pull the drug?
我违反了协议
I broke protocol.
她的结果将不计入试验
Her results are noabclonger admissible to the trial.
他们什么都不用做
They don't have to do anything.
要有别人生了肿瘤abc他们只需在标签上加个注明
Anyone else gets a tumor,abcthey'll put a warning on the label.
能保住执照?
Gonna keep your license?
如果我参与别的药物实验abc他们就会揭发我
They'll come after me if I attemptabcto participate in any more trials.
他们还算仁慈
That's very decent of them.
对我来说是好事
Well, good for me.
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
后天 大后天
And the next day. And the next day.
那不是你的柜子 是吗?
That wasn't your locker,was it?
柜子要上锁的
It's a lock-er room.
他们还没学会么?
How else are they gonna learn?
你觉得 没有孩子不快乐?
Do you think you can't beabchappy without a kid?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道没你就不会快乐
I know I can't be happy without you.
你打鼾
you snore.
别说了
Shut up.